Joyce Carol Oates Papers
Joyce Carol Oates Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Stull, William L. (Box 13A)
  - Styron, William (Box 13A)
  - Suarez, Virgil (Box 13A)
  - Sulieman, Ezra N. (Box 13A)
  - Sutton, Walter (Box 13A)
  - Swados, Harvey (Box 13A)
  - Swenson, May (Box 13A)
  - Sylvester, Janet (Box 13A)
  - Sylvester & Orphanos (Box 13A)
  - Syracuse University, 2 folders (Box 13A)
  - Szeman, Sherri (Box 13A)
  - Szuch, Yolanda Danyi (Box 13A)
  - T (Box 13B)
  - Talbots (Box 13B)
  - Talese, Gay (Box 13B)
  - Talese, Nan (Box 13B)
  - The Tamarack Press (Box 13B)
  - Tammaro, Thom (Box 13B)
  - Tannen, Deborah (Box 13B)
  - Tanner, Ron (Box 13B)
  - Tanner, Tony (Box 13B)
  - Tapon, Philippe (Box 13B)
  - Taylor, Robert (Box 13B)
  - Tegtmeyer, Ute (Box 13B)
  - Tenner, Edward (Box 13B)
  - Tenneson, Joyce (Box 13B)
  - Terrill, Kathryn (Box 13B)
  - Terry, Philip (Box 13B)
  - Theatre Quorum (Dallas, TX) (Box 13B)
  - Theroux, Alexander (Box 13B)
  - Theroux, Paul (Box 13B)
  - Thomas, James (Box 13B)
  - Thomas, Lewis (Box 13B)
  - Thon, Melanie Rae (Box 13B)
  - Ticknor & Fields, See Houghton Mifflin Company.
  - Tikkun (Box 13B)
  - Tilghman, Shirley M. (Box 13B)
  - Time Inc. Magazines (Box 13B)
  - The Times Literary Supplement (Box 13B)
  - Todd, David Y. (Box 13B)
  - Tomlinson, Charles (Box 13B)
  - Tompkins, Jane P. (Box 13B)
  - Toole, F. X. (Box 13B)
  - Torgovnick, Marianna (Box 13B)
  - Townley, Roderick (Box 13B)
  - Tracy, David (Box 13B)
  - Treat, Jessica (Box 13B)
  - Tremayne, Russell (Box 13B)
  - Trenner, Richard (Box 13B)
  - Trevor, Douglas (Box 13B)
  - Tribe, Laurence H. (Box 13B)
  - Tri Quarterly, See Gibbons, Reginald.
  - Tuchman, Barbara W. (Box 13B)
  - Turco, Lewis (Box 13B)
  - Turner, Frederick (Box 13B)
    See also The Kenyon Review.
  - Tuttle, Lisa (Box 13B)
  - Tuttleton, James W. (Box 13B)
  - Twichell, Chase (Box 13B)
  - 2 Plus 2 (Box 13B)
  - Tyler, Anne (Box 13B)
  - U (Box 13B)
  - Unger, Douglas (Box 13B)
  - Union League Club (New York, NY) (Box 13B)
  - University of Georgia (Box 13B)
  - University of Pittsburgh Press (Box 13B)
  - Unterberg Poetry Center (New York, NY) (Box 13B)
  - Upchurch, Michael (Box 13B)
  - Updike, John, 7 folders (Box 13B)
  - Urdang, Constance (Box 13B)
  - V (Box 13B)
  - Vanderbilt, Arthur (Box 13B)
  - Vanderbilt, Gloria, 5 folders of 9 (Box 13B)
  - Vanderbilt, Gloria, 4 folders of 9 (Box 13C)
  - Van Goethen, Nancy, See Joseph, Lawrence and Nancy Van Goethen.
  - Vanguard Press, Inc. (Box 13C)
  - Van Otteren, Juliet (Box 13C)
  - Vassar College (Box 13C)
  - Vecsey, George (Box 13C)
  - Verdelle, A. J. (Box 13C)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box 13C)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 13C)
  - Visionaire Publishing (Christopher Bollen) (Box 13C)
  - Vitale, Tom (Box 13C)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 13C)
  - W, 2 folders (Box 13C)
  - Waage, Frederick O. (Box 13C)
  - Wadsworth, Stephen (Box 13C)
  - Wagner-Martin, Linda (Box 13C)
  - Wakefield, Dan (Box 13C)
  - Wakoski, Diane (Box 13C)
  - Waldman, Mark Robert (Box 13C)
  - Waldron, Ann (Box 13C)
  - Walker, Alice (Box 13C)
  - Wallace, Marilyn (Box 13C)
  - Wallace, Ron (Box 13C)
  - Waller, Gary Fredric (Box 13C)
  - Wambaugh, Joseph (Box 13C)
  - Waren, Mark (Box 13C)
  - Warloe, Constance (Box 13C)
  - The Washington Post (Box 13C)
  - Watanabe, Nancy Ann (Box 13C)
  - Wayman, Tom (Box 13C)
  - Weaver, Will (Box 13C)
  - Weber, Katharine (Box 13C)
  - Weinberger, Eliot (Box 13C)
  - Weiss, Theodore Russell (Box 13C)
  - Weissman, Judith (Box 13C)
  - Wellman, Marc (Box 13C)
  - Welty, Eudora (Box 13C)
  - Wesley, Marilyn C. (Box 13C)
  - West, Paul (Box 13C)
  - Westdeutscher Rundfunk (Box 13C)
  - Westerfield, Nancy G. (Box 13C)
  - [Louise] Westergaard Productions, Inc. (Box 13C)
  - Western Humanities Review (Box 13C)
  - Whelan, Gloria, 6 folders (Box 13C)
  - Wheeler, Susan (Box 13C)
  - White, Edmund (Box 13C)
  - White, Linda (Box 13C)
  - White, Michael C. (Box 13C)
  - White, Milton (Box 13C)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art (Box 13C)
  - Whittlesey, Faith Ryan (Box 13C)
  - Wideman, John (Box 13C)
  - Wier, Allen (Box 13C)
  - Wiesenfarth, Joseph (Box 13C)
  - Wiggins, Marianne (Box 13C)
  - Wilbur, Ellen (Box 13C)
  - Wilkie, Brian (Box 13C)
  - William Morris Agency, Inc. (Box 13C)
  - Williams, Charles Kenneth (Box 13C)
  - Williams, Joy (Box 13C)
  - Williamsville South High School (Williamsville, NY) (Box 13C)
  - Wills, Gary (Box 13C)
  - Wilson, Colin (Box 13C)
  - Windnagle, Jean (Box 13C)
  - Winner, Robert (Box 13C)
  - Witness (Box 13C)
  - Witte, John (Box 13C)
  - Wolf, Leonard (Box 13C)
  - Wolfe, Peter (Box 13C)
  - Wolfe, Tom (Box 13C)
  - Wolff, Tobias (Box 13C)
  - Women's Ensemble Theatre Company (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 13C)
  - Women's Expressive Theatre, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 13C)
  - The Women's Press, Ltd. (Box 13C)
  - Women's Project (New York, NY) (Box 13C)
  - Women's Project and Productions, See Women's Project.
  - Woodcock, George (Box 13C)
  - Woodruff, Jay (Box 13C)
  - Worh, Irene (Box 13C)
  - Wright, Charles (Box 13C)
  - Wright, Doug (Box 13C)
  - Wright, Holly (Box 13C)
  - Wright, Stephen (Box 13C)
  - Wright, Tom (Box 13C)
  - Wright, William (Box 13C)
  - Writers Guild of America (Box 13C)
  - Wynand, Derk (Box 13C)
  - Wynn, Judith (Box 13C)
  - Y (Box 13C-2)
  - The Yale Review (Box 13C-2)
  - Yamamoto, Satoshi (Box 13C-2)
  - Yardley, Jonathan (Box 13C-2)
  - Yates, J. Michael (Box 13C-2)
  - Yellin, Herb (Box 13C-2)
  - Yoshioka, Yoko (Box 13C-2)
  - Young, Gary (Box 13C-2)
  - Z (Box 13C-2)
  - Zacharias, Lee (Box 13C-2)
  - Zeiler, Gail (Box 13C-2)
  - Zinober, Richard (Box 13C-2)
  - Zins, Daniel L. (Box 13C-2)
  - Ziolkowski, Theodore (Box 13C-2)
  - Zwart Water (Box 13C-2)
  - Unidentified
    - First name only, 2 folders (Box 13C-2)
    - Anonymous (Box 13C-2)
- Writings
  - Books
    - American Appetites
      - Early draft, notes, 4 folders (Box 13D)
      - Original ms., 3 folders (Box 13D)
      - Intermediate draft, 8 folders (Box 13D)
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 13D)
      - Production records (Box 13D)
        - Galley proofs
          - Author's set, 5 folders (Box 13D)
          - Master set
            - 1st pass, 3 folders (Box 13D)
            - 2nd pass, 5 folders (Box 13D, 14)
        - Page proofs (bound) (Box 14)
    - Angel Fire: Poems, Setting copy (Box 14)
    - Angel of Light
      - Original ms., 8 folders (Box 14)
      - Setting copy, 9 folders (Box 14)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs, 8 folders (Box 14)
    - The Assassins: a Book of Hours
      - Intermediate draft, 9 folders (Box 14, 15)
    - The Assignation: Stories
      - Intermediate draft, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart
      - Work sheets, 14 folders (Box 15)
      - Intermediate draft, 8 folders (Box 15)
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 15)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs
          - Author's set, 3 folders (Box 16)
          - Master set
            - 1st pass, 4 folders (Box 16)
            - 2nd pass, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Bellefleur
      - Work sheets / original ms., 8 folders (Box 16)
      - Intermediate draft
        - Carbon typescript, 13 folders (Box 16, 17)
        - Photocopy of typescript, 11 folders (Box 17)
      - Production records
        - Dust jacket (mounted) (Box 17)
    - Black Water
      - Work sheets (Box 17)
      - Intermediate draft, 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Setting copy (Box 17)
    - A Bloodsmoor Romance
      - Work sheets (Box 17)
      - Early draft, 5 folders (Box 17)
      - Intermediate draft, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Setting copy, 11 folders (Box 17, 18)
      - Production records: (Dutton), 1982
        - Galley proofs, 9 folders (Box 18)
        - Dust jacket (Box 18)
      - Production records: (Cape), 1983
        - Page proofs, 9 folders (Box 18)
    - Broke Heart Blues
      - Work sheets, 8 folders (Box 18, 19)
    - By the North Gate
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Childwold
      - Intermediate draft, 5 folders (Box 19)
    - Come Meet Muffin!, Ms. draft (Box 19)
    - Contraries
      - Intermediate draft, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Crossing the Border
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - The Crosswicks Horror
      - Original ms., 5 folders (Box 19, 20)
      - Intermediate draft "2nd draft", 6 folders (Box 20)
      - Intermediate draft "3rd draft", 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Cybele
      - Carbon typescript, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Demon and Other Tales, Production records; Page proofs (Box 20)
    - Do With Me What You Will
      - Setting copy, 11 folders (Box 20, 21)
      - Production records
        - Front matter (Box 21)
    - Double Delight [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Work sheets, 4 folders (Box 21)
      - Intermediate draft (partial) (Box 21)
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 6 folders (Box 21)
    - The Edge of Impossibility: Forms of Tragic Literature
      - Setting copy (bound) (Box 21)
    - Expensive People
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - First Love
      - Work sheets (Box 21)
      - Intermediate draft (Box 21)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 21)
      - Page proofs (Box 21)
    - Foxfire
      - Work sheets, 6 folders (Box 21, 22)
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 5 folders (Box 22)
    - A Garden of Earthly Delights
      - Intermediate draft, 6 folders (Box 22)
      - Intermediate draft (photocopy), 6 folders (Box 22)
    - George Bellows: American Artist, Work sheets; typescript ms. (Box 22)
    - The Goddess and Other Women: Stories
      - Intermediate draft, 6 folders (Box 22)
    - Haunted: Tales of the Grotesque
      - Typescript ms., 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Typescript ms., 4 folders (Box 23)
      - Setting copy, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Heat and Other Stories
      - Typescript ms., 7 folders (Box 23)
      - Setting copy "final draft", 7 folders (Box 23)
    - I Lock My Door Upon Myself
      - Work sheets, 4 folders (Box 23)
      - Typescript ms., 2 folders (Box 24)
      - Typescript ms. "final" (Box 24)
    - In Darkest America, See Writings: Scripts
    - Last Days: Stories
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 24)
    - Lives of the Twins [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Intermediate draft, 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Man Crazy
      - Work sheets, 3 folders (Box 24)
      - Typescript ms., Jan. 2, 1996; 5 folders (Box 24)
    - Marriages and Infidelities, Intermediate draft (bound) (Box 24)
    - Marya: a Life
      - Early draft, 8 folders (Box 24, 25)
      - Intermediate draft, 4 folders (Box 25)
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 25)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs
          - Master set - 1st pass, 6 folders (Box 25)
          - Master set - 2nd pass, 4 folders (Box 25)
          - Author's set, 5 folders (Box 25)
    - My Heart Laid Bare
      - Work sheets, 15 folders (Box 25, 26)
    - Mysteries of Winterthurn
      - Typescript ms. / work sheets, 24 folders (Box 26)
      - Setting copy, 10 folders (Box 27)
    - The Negro-Lover
      - Work sheets, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Nemesis [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Typescript ms. / work sheets, 10 folders (Box 27)
      - Intermediate draft, 6 folders (Box 27)
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 27, 28)
    - New Heaven, New Earth: the Visionary Experience in Literature
      - Setting copy, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Night-Side: Short Stories
      - Intermediate draft, 5 folders (Box 28)
    - On Boxing
      - Setting copy, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Production records
        - Page proofs (Box 28)
    - The Poisoned Kiss and Other Stories
      - Setting copy, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - The Profane Art: Essays and Reviews
      - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 28)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs (Box 28)
    - Raven's Wing and Other Stories
      - Work sheets, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Intermediate draft, 4 folders (Box 28)
    - The Rise of Life on Earth
      - Work sheets, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms., 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Typescript ms. "final" (Box 28)
    - A Sentimental Education
      - Setting copy, 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Production records
        - Page proofs, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Snake Eyes [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Work sheets, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Typescript ms. "final", 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Typescript ms., copyedited, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Setting copy (photocopy), 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Solstice
      - Work sheets, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Intermediate draft, 5 folders (Box 30)
      - Setting copy, 3 folders (Box 30)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs - author's set, 4 folders (Box 30)
    - Son of the Morning
      - Intermediate draft, 6 folders (Box 30)
    - Soul/Mate [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Work sheets, 6 folders (Box 30)
      - Intermediate draft, 6 folders (Box 30)
      - Typescript ms. "final", 7 folders (Box 30, 31)
      - Setting copy, 3 folders (Box 31)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs
          - "Author's set" (Box 31)
          - "Marked set" (Box 31)
          - "Master set" (Box 31)
          - "1st revised master set" (Box 31)
    - Starr Bright Will Be With You Soon [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Work sheets, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - them, Setting copy (bound) (Box 31)
    - The Time Traveler
      - Typescript ms., copyedited, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs (Box 31)
        - Galley proofs - author's set (Box 31)
        - Page proofs, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - The Triumph of the Spider Monkey: Play, Intermediate draft; Playscript; Additional pages (Box 31)
    - Twelve Plays
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Unholy Loves
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Upon the Sweeping Flood
      - Typescript ms., 4 folders (Box 32)
      - Galleys (bound) (Box 32)
    - We Were the Mulvaneys
      - Work sheets, 9 folders (Box 32)
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 10 folders (Box 33)
      - Setting copy, 9 folders (Box 33)
    - What I Lived For
      - Work sheets, 11 folders (Box 33, 34)
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 8 folders (Box 34)
      - Setting copy, 8 folders (Box 34)
    - Where Is Here?
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 4 folders (Box 35)
    - Will You Always Love Me?
      - Typescript ms. "July 1995", 6 folders (Box 35)
    - With Shuddering Fall
      - Typescript ms., 4 folders (Box 35)
    - (Woman) Writer: Occasions and Opportunities
      - Setting copy, 6 folders (Box 35)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs
          - Author's set
            - 1st pass, 5 folders (Box 35)
            - 2nd pass, 6 folders (Box 35, 36)
        - Galley proofs, 6 folders (Box 36)
    - Women Whose Lives Are Food: Men Whose Lives Are Money: Poems, Setting copy (Box 36)
    - Wonderland
      - Setting copy, 9 folders (Box 36)
    - You Can't Catch Me [Rosamond Smith title]
      - Work sheets, 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Typescript ms., 4 folders (Box 36)
      - Setting copy, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - You Must Remember This
      - Work sheets, 31 folders (Box 36, 37)
      - Intermediate draft, 11 folders (Box 37, 38)
      - Replaced and deleted pages, 5 folders (Box 38)
      - Setting copy, 9 folders (Box 38)
      - Production records
        - Galley proofs
          - Author's set, 7 folders (Box 38)
          - Master set - 1st pass, 7 folders (Box 38)
          - Master set - 2nd pass, 6 folders (Box 38)
    - Zombie
      - Work sheets (Box 39)
      - Typescript ms. "ribbon copy", 3 folders (Box 39)
      - Setting copy, 2 folders (Box 39)
      - Production records
        - Page proofs, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Essays
    - "After Amnesia", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; The New Yorker - galleys (Box 40)
    - Afterwords by Joyce Carol Oates
      - The Assignation, Typescript ms. (Box 40)
      - Expensive People (Ontario Review Press, 1990: "Expensive People: The Confessions of a 'Minor Character'"), Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 40)
      - Haunted: Tales of the Grotesque ("Afterword: Reflections on the Grotesque"), Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Photocopy of published essay (Box 40)
      - Twelve Plays, Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Photocopy of published essay (Box 40)
      - Where Are You Going, Where Have You Been?, Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 40)
      - Wonderland (Ontario Review Press, 1992: "Wonderland Revisited"), Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 40)
    - "The Alchemy of Antony and Cleopatra" Bucknell Review, Mar. 1964; signed "J. Oates Smith" (Box 40)
    - "The Ambiguity of Troilus and Cressida" Shakespeare Quarterly, Spring 1966; signed "author's copy" (Box 40)
    - "American Gothic" The New Yorker, May 8, 1995; Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "An American Tragedy" The New York Times Book Review, Jan. 24, 1971 (Box 40)
    - "And God Saw That It Was Good", Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "Anne Sexton: 'The Almost Unnameable Lust'", Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "Art and Ethics? - the (F)utility of Art", Work sheets; Salmagundi, Summer 1996 (Box 40)
    - "The Art of Being No One", Typescript ms.; The New York Times, July 22, 1996 (Box 40)
    - "The Art of Matt Phillips", Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "The Art of Suicide" [n.p.], undated (Box 40)
    - "Art: Therapy and Magic", Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "Aspects of the Self" The American Poetry Review, Jan./Feb. 1974 (Box 40)
    - "Behind the Wheel of the Miami Device" Quality, Winter [no year] (Box 40)
    - "Caption: What's in a Picture?", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Civilization, Feb./Mar. 1997 (Box 40)
    - "Cherished Moments" Life, Fall 1988 (Box 40)
    - "The Comedy of Metamorphosis in The Revenger's Tragedy" Bucknell Review, undated; photocopy (Box 40)
    - "Coming Home", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; USAir Magazine, May 1995 (Box 40)
    - "Confronting Head On the Face of the Afflicted", Work sheets (working title: "Art and 'Victim Art'"); Typescript ms.; The New York Times, Feb. 19, 1995 (Box 40)
    - "Conrad's Youth", Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "A Conversation with Margaret Atwood", Typescript ms. (Box 40)
    - "A Corner to Write In", Work sheets (working title: "Sacred, Sentimental Places"); Typescript ms. (working title: "Turn Clock Forward, Never Backward"); Elle Décor, Oct. 1991 (Box 40)
    - "David Hanson's Colstrip, Montana Series", Typescript ms.; American Art, Spring 1992 (Box 40)
    - "Delirium and Detachment" (journal excerpt), The New Yorker - galleys; The New Yorker, July 3, 1995 (Box 40)
    - "The Diceman Numbeth", Typescript ms. (working title: "Andrew Dice Clay: Guaranteed to Offend"); Entertainment Weekly, July 27, 1990 (Box 40)
    - "Does the Writer Exist?" The New York Times Book Review, Apr. 22, 1984 (Box 40)
    - "Dracula (Tod Browning, 1931): The Vampire's Secret", Work sheets (Box 40)
    - "The Essential Emily Dickinson" The Boston Book Review, Sept. 1996 (Box 41)
    - "Failure in the Desert" The Village Voice, Mar. 24, 1987 (Box 41)
    - "Fall From Grace" The New York Times Book Review, Dec. 17, 1995 (Box 41)
    - "Female Sexuality / Female Spirituality", Typescript ms.; Mademoiselle, July 1971 (Box 41)
    - "The 'Fifth Act' and the Chorus in the English and Scottish Ballads" The Dalhousie Review v. 42, no. 3, signed "author's copy" (Box 41)
    - "Floyd Patterson: the Essence of a Competitor", Work sheets (Box 41)
    - "Advertisement" [n.p.], undated (Box 41)
    - "Food Mysteries", Work sheets (Box 41)
    - Forewords by Joyce Carol Oates
      - Metaphysical Tales / by Eugene K. Garber, typescript carbon with corrections (Box 41)
      - Saving Graces: the Images of Women in European Cemeteries by David Robinson, Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 41)
    - "The Formidable W. B. Yeats" The New York Times Book Review, Sept. 7, 1969 (Box 41)
    - "Franz Kafka's In the Penal Colony" for You've Got to Read This, Typescript mss. (Box 41)
    - "From The Life of the Writer and the Life of the Career: First Principles and 'Transformations of Play'", Work sheets; New Literary History, Spring 1996 (Box 41)
    - "The Greatest of Gifts", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Life, Dec. 1990 (Box 41)
    - "Home Away from Home" Syracuse Herald-Journal, May 16, 1995 (Box 41)
    - "Hunter's Harvest", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Playboy [n.d.] (Box 41)
    - "I Had No Other Thrill or Happiness", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; The New York Review of Books, Mar. 24, 1994 (Box 41)
    - "I, the Juror", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Witness, v. 5,no. 2, 1991 (photocopy) (Box 41)
    - "An Illusory and Hopeful Celebration" Monthly Detroit, Dec. 1981 (Box 41)
    - "I'm Caught Up in the Novel" [n.p.], undated (Box 41)
    - "In Olden Times, When Wishing Was Having....", Work sheets (Box 41)
    - "Intellectual Seduction: Meeting with Gorbachev", Intermediate draft (working title: "Meeting the Gorbachevs"); The New York Times Magazine, Jan. 3, 1988 (Box 41)
    - Introductions by Joyce Carol Oates
      - American Gothic Tales / edited by Joyce Carol Oates, Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 41)
      - The Best American Essays 1991/ edited by Joyce Carol Oates, Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 41)
      - The Best American Short Stories 1979/ selected and edited by Joyce Carol Oates, Typescript carbon (with corrections) (Box 41)
      - The Essential Dickinson / selected by Joyce Carol Oates, Work sheets; Photocopy of published essay (Box 41)
      - The Philosopher's Stone / by Colin Wilson, Typescript ms. (Box 41)
      - Tales of H.P. Lovecraft / selected and introduced by Joyce Carol Oates, Typescript ms.; Photocopy of published essay (Box 41)
    - "The Introduction to Wurthering Heights", c1988; New York: Time Warner Libraries (Box 41)
    - "Ionesco's Dances of Death" Thought, Autumn 1965; offprint, signed "author's copy" (Box 41)
    - "Is This the Promised End?: the Tragedy of King Lear' The Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, Fall 1974; signed "author's copy" (Box 41)
    - "'JCO' and I", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Antaeus - page proofs; Concord, N.H.: William B. Ewert, c1994 (Box 41)
    - "Jocoserious Joyce", Typescript ms.; Critical Inquiry, Summer 1976 - offprints (2), one signed "author's copy" (Box 41)
    - "Kid Dynamite" Life, Mar. 1987 (Box 41)
    - "A Letter to My Mother, Carolina Oates, On Her 78th Birthday", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; The New York Times Magazine, May 12, 1996 (Box 42)
    - "'Lewis Carroll' and Alice in Wonderland", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "Lightning Bolt", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "A Lockport Memoir" The Buffalo News, Apr. 2, 1989 (Box 42)
    - "Love on Film" McCall's, Oct. 1970 (Box 42)
    - "The Love She Searched For" Time, Sept. 15, 1997 (Box 42)
    - "The Madness of Art" The Newsletter of the HWA, Inc., July/Aug. 1994 (Box 42)
    - "The Madness of Art: Henry James's The Middle Years", Work sheets; New Literary History, Spring 1996 (Box 42)
    - "The Making of a Writer", Typescript ms.; The New York Times Book Review, July 11, 1982 (Box 42)
    - "Melville and the Manichean Illusion"; Studies in Literature and Language, Spring 1962; two signed copies, one designated "author's copy" (Box 42)
    - "The Motive for Writing", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "The Motives of Poetry", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "My Fascination with Boxing" Princeton Alumni Weekly, Apr. 8, 1987 (Box 42)
    - "My Father, My Fiction", Work sheets (working title: "Family Mysteries"); Typescript ms.; The New York Times Magazine, Mar. 19, 1989 (Box 42)
    - "The Mysterious Mr. Thoreau" The New York Times Book Review, May 1, 1988 (Box 42)
    - "The Mythos of the 'Killer Instinct'", Ms. drafts (Box 42)